荷兰欢迎您
杰里米 克拉克森
理查德 哈蒙德
詹斯 妹的
翻译
natas Geoff Alan
OckRazor Oliver
校对
natas Monica-卡 Geoff RN
时间轴
Monica-卡 natas RN
Hello, everybody.
大家好
Hello. Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Hello.
大家好
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you so much.
非常感谢
Hello, everybody. Welcome to the Grand Tour,
大家好 欢迎来到The Grand Tour
which, this week, comes from the Netherlands.
这周我们来到荷兰啦
We're setting something of a record, actually,
我们已经创记录了
cos we are the first three British men ever to come here for a weekend
我们仨是第一个周末到荷兰
and not vomit on a prostitute.
却没吐在妓女身上的英国人
Actually, we love coming to Holland.
事实上我们很喜欢来荷兰
James for his... for his own reasons.
詹姆斯有他自己的理由
飞了叶子肚子饿
And I like it because the Dutch are officially
我喜欢这儿 因为荷兰人
the tallest people on earth.
是正儿八经世界上最高的
It's true. True fact.
真的没骗你们
-Yes, and I hate it here. I'm sick of...
没错我恨这个地方
I'm sick of staring at belly buttons all day.
我受够从早到晚只能盯着肚脐看了
The only problem I do have here is that I'm not allowed to use the word "swaffelen".
我对这地方唯一的不满就是不能用swaffling这个词
Well, you just did, didn't you?
但你刚刚就说了啊
swaffling 本意为把丁丁甩来甩去
No, the thing is, OK, it is a really bad word here,
是啊这个词本身就相当粗俗
这里指曾经的一段youtube视频
一个荷兰学生用丁丁拍打泰姬陵墙壁
and I have no idea why.
我完全不懂为什么
最终使swaffling成为2008荷兰年度词
-What does it mean? -It means...
-它什么意思 -它的意思是
It means to bang your gentleman sausage...
它的意思是用你的男士香肠
...on the side of the Taj Mahal.
去拍打泰姬陵的墙壁
-Oh, God!
天啊
Anyway, listen. Erm...
不管怎样
We're in Rotterdam, which is a marvellous city, in fact,
我们在鹿特丹 这是一个绝佳的城市
because you aren't allowed to bring a car into the city -
因为你不允许开这些车进城
a petrol car - if it was built before 1992.
汽油车 1992年之前的汽油车
You aren't allowed to bring a diesel car into the city if it was built before 2000,
或者不能开2000年以前的柴油车进城
which means you're never held up by poor people.
就是说不会有穷人来堵你路了
-Really? -What else can we say about the Dutch?
-真的么 -荷兰还有啥
-Oh, of course, you gave the world speed cameras. -Oh, yeah.
-当然你给世界带来了测速摄像头 -没错
荷兰人发明了测速摄像头
-So thank you very much for that. -Thank you.
-太谢谢你们了 -谢谢
No, actually, I'd far rather be pulled over
实际上我更愿意被
by the actual Dutch police rather than a speed camera,
荷兰警察拦下来而不是被摄像头逮到
cos, boy, oh, boy, do these guys look good.
因为老天啊这些哥们看起来好棒
-We've got a picture here. -Whoa!
-这有张图 -哇
I would very much like to see a lady policeman in an outfit like that.
我超想看女警察穿这一身
-It looks like the guy on the right already has.
最右那哥们应该已经看到了
-Shall we get on with the show... man?
我们能继续节目吗 老兄
Yes, good idea. Er...
好的好主意
And coming up in our programme about cars this week...
本周我们这关于车的节目里有
I try to pull a camel.
我试着拉骆驼
Come on. Come on.
来啊 来啊
A donkey pulls James.
驴拉着詹姆斯
And Richard gets stuck in a cow orgy.
理查德困在群交的牛里
I-I really am alarmed.
我 我很警觉了
But first, there's been a bit of an argument in the office between these two.
但首先 办公室里这两人争个不休
You see, Richard maintains
因为理查德认为
that the Mazda MX-5 is all the sports car you would ever need.
马自达MX-5是你唯一需要的跑车
-Because it is. -Mm-hm. But James says it isn't.
-因为它就是啊 -但詹姆斯说它不是
Because it isn't.
因为它不是
So we decided they should sort it out
因此我们觉得他们该比比看
by going to the obvious proving ground for all sports cars:
这就得去世上最正统的跑车试炼之地
North Africa.
北非
马 拉 喀 什
RICHARD: This is it,
就是它了
the latest version of the bestselling two-seater roadster of all time.
最畅销的双座敞篷跑车的最新款
And it's easy to see why.
叫座的原因很明显
Peppy little engine at the front,
热辣的小引擎在前
two seats in the open air in the middle, rearwheel drive.
双座在中 蓝天入怀 后轮驱动
It's the perfect sports-car recipe.
这是完美的跑车配方
But layered on top of that in this new version
但在这新款里
you get air conditioning, heated seats,
你有空调 座椅加热
lane-departure assist, cruise control,
车道辅助 定速巡航
rain-sensing wipers, dusk-sensing headlamps.
自动雨刮 自动大灯
You just can't do any better.
没法做更好了
Well, you can, actually, because all of those luxury items you're mentioning now,
当然能 因为你说的这些豪华配置
they just add weight, and they mean it isn't a true sports car any more.
只会增加重量 它不再是正宗的跑车了
-Yes, it is. -No, it isn't.
-它就是啊 -它不是
Colin Chapman, he was the bloke who founded Lotus,
科林 查普曼 路特斯的创始人
he said the ethos of a sports car is simplify and add lightness.
他说跑车的精髓就是极简再加轻量化
He didn't say you simplify and add electric windows.
他没说是极简再加电动车窗
Yep, and then he gave all his money away to a drug dealer called John DeLorean.
是啊 然后他把所有的钱给了个叫约翰 德罗林的毒贩子
约翰德罗林 DeLorean车厂创始人
This, ladies and gentlemen, is what it's actually about.
女士们先生们 这才像话
This is called the Zenos.
这车叫Zenos
后因贩毒被捕 最终导致DeLorean车厂倒闭
查普曼曾参与其在北爱尔兰建厂计划
You get four wheels, you get somewhere to sit, an engine, and that's it.
你有四个轮子 有地方坐 有发动机 就这样
并使超千万英镑的国家补贴流失
It's a sports car.
这是辆跑车
-Yeah. What do you do if it rains? -Well, you'd get wet.
-是啊 要是下雨了怎么办 -你就湿身了
What if you want to listen to the radio?
要是想听广播呢
Why would I want to listen to the radio around here?
为什么我要在这听广播
-Does it have a heater? -No.
-它带暖风吗 -不
-Has it got windows? -Look, if you buy a football boot,
-你有窗子吗 -听着 你买双足球鞋
you don't expect it to be usable as a ballet shoe, do you?
你不需要它有芭蕾舞鞋的功能
But Mazda has invented a football boot that you can wear to the opera.
但马自达发明了能穿去听歌剧的足球鞋
Look, I can guarantee that if you wear that shoe to the opera house...
我保证你要是穿足球鞋去歌剧院
RICHARD: At this point, the director said
这时导演说
he'd heard enough about shoes for one day...
他今天听够鞋子的事了
...and told us to go for a drive.
让我们出去开一圈
Right, now I'm away from Hammond's luxury sports car resort,
我已离开哈蒙德的豪华跑车度假区
let me tell you a little bit about this remarkable car.
我就聊聊这超赞的车吧
It's powered by the 2L turbocharged engine
它的动力来自福克斯ST
from the Ford Focus ST, giving 250 horsepower.
2.0涡轮增压引擎 250匹马力
That's mounted in the middle, right behind my head there,
位于车子中间 就在我脑袋后面
driving the rear wheels through a no-nonsense,
驱动后轮的是套不说废话
old-school six-speed gearbox.
老派的六速变速箱
Now, 250 horsepower doesn't sound like a huge amount in the modern world,
250匹在现今车坛听起来不大
but this car, made with an aluminium spine
但这车 全铝车架
and composite tub, and all the rest of it,
复合材料驾驶舱 之类的
weighs less than three quarters of a tonne,
车重还不到750千克
so it is genuinely quick.
所以它真是非常快
Look... Whoa!
瞧啊
It makes the noise of some futuristic propulsion system powered by antimatter.
它的声浪像是由反物质驱动的未来派推进器
Yes! Electrifying!
好让人兴奋
James comes from a world where he wants his phone and his camera separate.
在詹姆斯世界 手机和相机要分开用
"I like a paper diary."
我喜欢纸质日记本
This Mazda is a smartphone. It does everything.
这马自达是智能手机 啥都能干
It looks brilliant, it will be endlessly reliable, it's fast,
看着好看 肯定无比耐用 跑得快
it's got speakers in the headrests, and it handles well.
头枕里还有音箱 操控还那么好
And you can get an MX-5 from ?18,500.
MX-5售价只要18500英镑
James's car starts at ?33,000,
詹姆斯的车起价要33000
and you don't even get doors!
而且连车门都没有
My shed has got doors.
我的棚子都有门呢
I furnish my cats with doors.
我家猫的窝都有门
You need doors.
你需要门啊
I bet he's being shaken to death in that thing.
我打赌他在那车里会颠死
I bet Hammond thinks I'm being shaken to death in here,
我赌哈蒙德觉得我会颠死
but actually he's wrong,
实际上他错了
because this isn't like a BAC Mono or a Radical.
因为这车和BAC MONO还有Radical不一样
It is obviously very much a car for taking on the track,
当然它是为了赛道打造的车
but it's been tuned for road use.
但它的调校也照顾日常使用
It's quite supple.
它很灵活
See? Look.
你瞧
Bump. It's all right.
颠一下又怎样
I'm very relaxed.
我很放松啊
JAMES: Eventually, we pulled over for a cup of coffee
最终 我们停了下来喝杯咖啡
and a bit more arguing about doors.
继续争执着门
Just because they had them in the 12th century
只因为12世纪的教堂里就有
12世纪马拉喀什建城 标志性建筑就是其城门
on cathedrals, whatever, you don't need them now.
不代表现在也要啊
Don't be a slave to convention.
不要做陈规的奴隶
But people had eyelids in the 12th century,
但12世纪的人也有眼皮啊
and nobody's deciding, "Let's get rid of those, they're old hat."
也没人决定 那玩意扔了 不中用
"Oh, no! I've got dust in my eyes and I can't sleep."
糟糕 我眼睛进灰了 我没法睡觉了
That's completely facile, Hammond. You know exactly what I mean.
这完全是信口开河 你明知我的意思
The door... I mean, Riva speedboats don't have doors.
你看 Riva快艇就没有门
You don't say...
你不说
This is lovely, isn't it?
这地方好棒啊
What are you doing here?
你来这干嘛
Well, word reached me that you two were talking rubbish.
我听说你俩在瞎扯
-What do you mean, "rubbish"? -Well, if you want the best sports car,
-什么瞎扯 -如果你想要最好的跑车
you don't want a Mazda or a Zenos. You want--
肯定不是马自达或Zenos 你要的是
Oh, God. He's brought an Alfa Romeo.
天啊他开了辆阿尔法罗密欧
Yes, of course I have.
是啊当然啦
Alfa Romeo 4C Spider.
阿尔法罗密欧 4C Spider
JEREMY: This is what I'm talking about.
我说的就是它
A symphony in carbon fibre.
一首碳纤维的交响乐
Balance personified.
一具平衡的化身
The Graduate updated.
一部进化的史诗
A mini Ferrari, as cute as a bunny rabbit,
一辆迷你法拉利 萌得像个小白兔
with the greatest badge in the history of mo--
身上还挂着汽车史上最伟大的标识
How much is it?
它有多贵
-You know perfectly well how much it is. -Yeah, we've forgotten.
-你们明知道它的价钱 -我们忘了
Money is vulgar.
谈钱很俗
You can't put a price on something as exquisite as that.
这么优美的东西是无法计价的
Yeah, but Alfa Romeo did put a price on it, didn't they?
但阿尔法罗密欧就是给它计价了
And what was it?
多少钱
-Sixty thousand pounds.
60000英镑
So you could have both of our cars and everything in the back of shot
所以你可以拥有这两辆车 还有目之所及的一切
for the price of one of these Alfa Romeos?
来换这一辆阿尔法罗密欧
I know, it is extraordinary value for money.
我知道 这实在是太值了
-It's too far from outside to inside. -It's miles!
-跨到车里的距离太长了 -好长啊
JEREMY: Yes, thick sills...
没错 厚门槛
-Here we go. -...for strength.
-进去了 -为了刚性
Look at this, rotary heater knobs.
看这啊 旋钮式暖风开关
-It's like being in the 1970s. -Yeah, it is, actually.
-就像回到70年代了 -真的没错
This handbrake, look at that.
这个手刹 你看啊
Is that fixed on or does that come off?
是装上了还是要掉了
Alfa Romeo, purveyors of disappointment for nearly three decades.
阿尔法罗密欧 三十年来专业让人失望
RICHARD: Look at this. Classy.
看看这 漂亮
RICHARD: Yeah. Feel the quality in that. JAMES: Let me feel that.
-感受下这质量 -让我体验一下
RICHARD: Mm. JAMES: Sixty thousand pounds?!
-嗯 -60000英镑
RICHARD: Mm. And this...
嗯 还有这
That's what you want to hear.
这声音好正
If you ever buy a new item of clothing, never show it these two.
如果你买了新衣服 千万别给他们看
"What are you wearing that jacket for? It makes you look like a German gameshow host."
你穿那夹克干嘛 它让你像德国综艺节目主持人
RICHARD: That's satisfying.
真让人满足
JAMES: Why are you wearing that jacket?
你穿那夹克干嘛
Because I was at a party in India last night,
因为我昨晚在印度派对
and I've hurried over here.
我直接赶过来了
RICHARD: Why did you go to the party
为什么你去派对
dressed as a German gameshow host?
穿得像德国综艺节目主持人
JEREMY: Soon, I grew weary of their abuse
很快 我受够了他们恶言相向
and set off in what, be in no doubt,
然后开着 毫无疑问
is my favourite car on sale today.
现售车里我的最爱 上路了
I will admit, there are one or two tiny little problems with the 4C.
我承认 4C有一两个很小的问题
Trivial stuff.
细枝末节啦
It's very wide. The gearbox is a little bit dim-witted.
它很宽 变速箱有点点笨
If you fit sports exhausts, the noise is catastrophic.
如果选装运动排气 噪音简直是灾难
The petrol tank... yeah, that's too small.
油箱 恩 太小
You've really only got a range of 300... yards.
只能续航个270...米
And then there's the steering.
然后就是转向
There's no power assistance, so it's incredibly heavy when you're parking,
没有助力 所以停车时候相当费劲
there's no feel when you're on the move.
开起来是没啥感觉
And then, and this is its party piece,
然后它就有自己的娱乐节目
just occasionally, it'll go violently left or right for no reason.
时不时的 它会猛地向左或向右打 毫无理由
Whoa! You see that?
喔 你看到了吧
Bloody hell.
太可怕了
But look at it this way, we could all probably find fault with our children,
但要这样看 我们都会在孩子身上找到缺点
and yet... we still love them.
但我们还是 爱着他们
RICHARD: Jeremy loves Alfa Romeos
杰里米喜欢阿尔法罗密欧
because, back in the old days,
因为 回到以前
they were great... but they're not any more.
他们很伟大 但辉煌不再了啊
Plenty of things were great.
很多东西曾经伟大过
Greece.
希腊
Rolf Harris.
罗尔夫 哈瑞斯
澳大利亚艺人 作曲家 84岁时因性骚扰入狱
You can't love them now.
现在他们没人喜欢啊
Another small problem with the Alfa
还有一个我之前没提的
that I didn't mention earlier
阿尔法的小毛病
is that you get cramp after five minutes.
开5分钟就会抽筋
I'm gonna have to stop and go for a walk,
我要停下来 舒展下经络了
and they'll want to know why,
他们会好奇怎么了
and I'll have to tell them I need a wee or something.
我会告诉他们 我要尿尿之类
No, diarrhoea.
不 拉肚子了
Sorry, I've got to stop. I've got to stop.
抱歉 我得停一下 得停一下
RADIO: I'm just stopping for a minute here. Hang on.
我就停一下 等会
Why are you stopping for a minute?
你干嘛要停一下
JEREMY: Ohhh! Nothing.
没啥
Well, why are you hopping about?
你跳什么跳
Look at the snowy mountains.
看那雪山连绵
You are welcome to Morocco.
欢迎来摩洛哥
Ah, merci, monsieur. Comment ca va?
啊 谢谢先生 你好啊
JAMES: God above.
老天
-Have you got cramp? -No.
-你是抽筋了么 -没
Yes, you have.
你就抽着呢
Right, good. Well, I've seen the view.
好了 我看好风景了
I just wanted to see the view, and it's lovely.
我就想看看风景 很美妙
JEREMY: Back on the road, James suddenly delivered
回到路上 詹姆斯突然发表了
a very un-James-manlike observation.
一个很不船长的评价
My car is seriously quick!
我这车真是快啊
It's not as fast as this.
没这辆快啊
Yeah, I bet it is.
我赌比你快
James, this has a turbocharged 1750cc engine
詹姆斯 它有来自菲亚特朋多的
from a Fiat Punto.
1.75升涡轮发动机
Mine's 2L with a twin-scroll turbocharger.
我的是2升 双涡管涡轮发动机
Have you noticed Hammond is being strangely quiet on the subject of speed?
你注意到哈蒙德在速度这话题上很安静么
Oh, just listening to you two bicker.
哦就听你俩争个不停
I am a bit down on power, if I'm honest.
我的车动力不足 我承认
I think Hammond's in a sort of retirement home for former distressed sports-car owners.
哈蒙德好似待在疗养院 那里满是忧虑的前跑车车主
JEREMY:  Right, next straight bit of road, James May,
好了 下个直路 詹姆斯
I will pull over and show you what real speed is.
我会靠边停车 给你见识下真正的速度
-Cows.
有牛
RICHARD:  On a roof rack. I've never seen that.
装在车顶上 我从没见过哎
JEREMY: Soon, we found a suitable stretch of road...
很快 我们找到了合适的路
...and Hammond agreed to be the starter.
哈蒙德同意来当发令人
-I've got launch control. -Not interested.
-我有弹射起步 -没兴趣
JEREMY: Are you ready? Before anyone comes.
准备好了么 趁没人来
RICHARD: In three, two, one, go!
三 二 一 走
Well, now, that's just impossible!
这完全不可能啊
It's the Zenos...
Zenos赢了
which means James May has just won a drag race.
就是说 詹姆斯竟赢了场直线加速赛
JEREMY: But for me, that wasn't the biggest surprise.
对我来说 这不是最震惊的
I don't understand why this lost,
我不懂它为什么会输
because instead of a conventional chassis,
不同于传统底盘
it has a carbon-fibre tub,
这车是碳纤维单体壳的
like you get in a Formula One car
就好比F1赛车
or a McLaren P1.
或者迈凯伦P1
And a carbon-fibre tub makes a car... expensive, but light.
碳纤维单体壳会让车很贵但很轻
Very light.
非常轻
I'm trying to work out why I lost that race.
我在想为啥会输掉比赛
I think it's cos your car isn't as fast as mine.
肯定是你的车没我快咯
RICHARD: That was a factor.
这是一个因素
Yeah, but mine is so light.
是啊但我车轻啊
RICHARD: How do you know it's light?
你怎么知道很轻
Every time Alfa say how much it weighs,
阿尔法每次宣称的车重
they give a different figure.
都会不一样
JEREMY: Yeah, that's because they've got
那是因为阿尔法有
better things to do than go around weighing cars.
比称重量更重要的事情
When Picasso had finished one of his paintings,
毕加索画完一幅画的时候
he didn't say, "Oh, I wonder how much that weighs."
肯定不会想这幅画有多重
You need to know the weight of an Alfa for when you resell it,
但你卖二手阿尔法时就要知道车重啊
because you buy scrap cars by weight.
因为报废车是按重量来卖的
JEREMY: With the Zenos, that was built in Norfolk,
你那辆Zenos 产地是诺福克
so obviously they're gonna weigh it - there's nothing else to do.
那个地方无聊至极 他们只能称车重玩
This is from Milan.
我这可是来自米兰
They finished making it, and then they went into town with one and pulled girls.
他们造完车 就开着进城把妹了
JAMES:  It's massive and it's made of pig iron,
你这车又大 还是用生铁造的
that's the problem.
问题就在这
I can see the carbon fibre...
我能看见你车上的碳纤维
JEREMY: The weight argument raged on for the rest of the journey.
关于车重的争议在剩下的旅程中一直持续
So, that night, at the hotel,
所以当晚 在酒店
I came up with a plan.
我想出一个点子
I'm gonna weigh all three cars
我会把三辆车都称重
to prove the Alfa's the lightest.
来证明阿尔法是最轻的
The problem with your plan is that you'd need a weighbridge, and...
但问题是需要地秤
-Yes. -Well, hang on.
-是啊 -等等
-Well, get one. -No, there isn't one.
-我会搞一个来 -这里并没有
I have got the hotel brochure here, actually,
我这有本酒店的册子
and, do you know, it's got three restaurants,
你知道吗 这酒店有三个餐厅
a spa, and a gym, a business centre, tennis court.
有SPA  健身房 商务中心 还有网球场
JEREMY: Mm-hm. -But with one glaring omission.
-继续 -但有个巨大的疏忽
-What? -There's no weighbridge.
-啥 -没有地秤
-No! -They haven't thought of that. I'd knock a star off.
-怎么会 -考虑不周 要摘掉一颗星了
I shall build one.
我自己造一个
I shall build a weighbridge, and then you shall see.
我自己造地秤 咱们走着瞧
-I will build a weighbridge. -That could have been
-我会造一个的 -那本应是
a really useful and interesting test, and you've ruined it.
一项实用且有趣的测试 但被你毁了
People are interested in Alfa Romeos!
人们对阿尔法罗密欧感兴趣啊
People are interested in murders, they don't want to see one.
人们对谋杀感兴趣 但并不想目睹啊
Anyway, anyway, we'll have more of that later on,
关于这个话题未完待续
but first, it is now time for us to engage reverse
但首先让我们挂上倒档
and park neatly in a marked space on Conversation Street.
缓缓停入唠嗑街
Right, now, which nation on earth has the worst police cars?
请问世界上哪个国家的警车最差劲
Oh, that's some good conversation. I like that one.
这个话题有意思 我喜欢
The worst police cars, it's definitely not the Americans, is it,
最糟的警车 肯定不是美国 对吧
because they have those Crown Vics, and they're rearwheel drive V8s.
他们用的皇冠维多利亚 后驱大V8
-That's what you need. -They're good police cars. Not the Americans.
-这才是称职的警车 -是好警车 排除美帝
-Erm... -It's us. It's the British.
-呃 -是我们 是英国
Yeah. We have those dreary little Vauxhall diesel Astras.
是啊 那无聊的柴油沃克斯豪尔 雅特
Opels if you live here.
那车在这挂欧宝标
Or, if you're in America, those miserable little Chevrolets
在美帝的话 就是那些小得可怜的雪弗莱
that are actually Daewoos. It's awful.
实际上它们是大宇 太次了
Most countries around the world
世界上大多数国家
would traditionally have always had a police car that was made there,
历来都会选用国产车
one of their own cars. Wouldn't they?
来当警车 不是么
And the funny thing is, that's not what they used to do here.
有趣的是 在荷兰却不一样
-In Holland? -No.
-荷兰 -是的
You don't surprise me.
我并不吃惊啊
What they actually had for many years, about 30 years, was Porsches.
很多年 大概30年来 它们一直用保时捷
-What? -The police used Porsches, yeah. Remember? Yeah.
-啥 -警车用保时捷 不记得了吗
-Do you know, I'd forgotten. You're right, they did. -They did.
-你是对的 我都差点忘了 -是真的
How did they persuade the government?
他们是怎么说服政府的
It's masterful. It's genius.
简直太机智 太有才
Absolute respect to everybody who did it.
为这些说服政府的人致敬
What they did was say, "Right, we need...
他们是这样说的 我觉得
Hm. I think we need a Porsche
我们得用保时捷
because it's air-cooled and the engine is at the back,
因为风冷发动机是后置的
and that would be handy if we have to reverse at high speed for a long time."
这样利于长时间高速倒车行驶
They actually said that?
真的是这样说的
They did. And this gets better.
真的 然而亮点在后面
And I'm not making this up. They did say this.
我没有胡编乱造 他们真的说过
They need a car where you can remove the roof
他们需要能够拆掉车顶的车
so you can stand on the seats to address traffic in an emergency situation.
所以在紧急情况下 就能站在座椅上指挥交通了
So what they need is a 911 Targa,
所以他们需要911 Targa
and matching sunglasses, I presume, yes.
以及配套的太阳镜 我猜
Did they also say, "And it comes with 911 on the back
他们是不是还说 它后面有911的车标
which is our telephone number"?
正好就是报警电话哦
The thing is, it doesn't, and they're still at it,
并没有 但是这种传统保留了下来
because the cycle cops around here,
因为这里骑自行车的警察们
and there's a lot of them,
这里很多警察骑自行车
they managed to persuade the government
他们成功说服政府
that they need mountain bikes.
给他们配备山地车
-What, here? -In Holland.
-在这里 -在荷兰
It's the flattest country on earth
这是世界上最平坦的国家
and they need mountain bikes!
却需要山地车
"Yes, I might see a mountain." What?!
我可能会碰到山哦 啥
The best thing...
更棒的是
The best thing is, it gives us an opportunity to have one more look
更棒的是 这就再给我们次机会
at a photograph of the Dutch mountain cop police.
看一眼荷兰山地警察的照片
-There they are.
看看他们
-Now, I want to talk about otters.
我想聊聊水獭
-What? -I want to talk about otters.
-啥 -我想讨论下水獭
You see, a few years ago somebody in Holland
几年前荷兰有人发现
worked out that there were only 185 otters in the entire country.
全国只有185只水獭
Yeah, Jeremy, it's a car show.
杰里米 我们这是汽车节目
Bear with me, OK, because I've got the figures here.
听我讲 因为我这里有数据
In 2014, 21 of these otters were run over.
2014年 有21只水獭被轧死
OK? In 2015, 49 were run over.
2015年 49只
You only have 185 otters in the whole country,
你们全国只有185只水獭啊
and in two years, you've flattened 70 of them under your cars.
两年你们就开车轧死了70只
-What is your problem with otters?!
水獭哪里惹你们了
The thing is that I don't want people to get the wrong impression.
我不想让大家对荷兰有错误的印象
I don't want everyone to think that Dutch people go around murdering animals.
我不想让大家觉得荷兰人喜欢虐杀动物
Let me explain.
让我来解释一下
Recently, the government here spent 150,000 euros,
最近 荷兰政府花费15万欧元
and that's ?150,000,
这相当于15万英镑
?160,000, ?170,000...
16万英镑 17万英镑
-That's Brexit for you.
这就是脱欧的后果
We can't even afford to put mayonnaise on our chips now any more.
我们再也买不起美乃滋来蘸薯条了
Er... Anyway, they spent 150,000 euros on a bridge over a road
他们花15万欧元修了座天桥
so squirrels could cross safely.
这样松鼠就能安全过马路了
We've got a picture of the bridge. It's a substantial thing.
这里有张桥的照片 不小的一座
You know this bridge? A famous bridge?
你们知道这座桥吗 很有名吗
-That's a squirrel bridge? -Yeah, it's a squirrel bridge.
-松鼠天桥么 -对 传说中的松鼠天桥
Anyway, how many squirrels do you think have used it?
那么你觉得有多少只松鼠用过
A squillion.
极大量的
I see where you're going with that one, James. No, it isn't.
詹姆斯我知道你的思路 但事与愿违
I've got the figures here.
我这里有组数据
"CCTV footage has revealed, in 2014,
录像显示 2014年
three squirrels used it.
有3只松鼠 用过这座桥
In 2015, it was used only twice."
到2015年 只用了2次
Well, why didn't the third squirrel use it again in 2015?
为啥2015年的时候第三只松鼠没出现
-It probably got run over. -Yeah.
-估计被车轧死了 -哈哈
By somebody mistaking him for an otter.
被某人错当成水獭了
Get it! Get it!
小样儿 搞死你
You've probably read the other day, the Dutch are taking a view
你也许知道 荷兰人正在探讨
on whether to allow people to...
是否应该
How can I put this? Assisted dying of somebody -
该怎么说呢 是否应该帮助某人安乐死
feels as though their life is complete, OK?
感觉他们的人生已经完整了
This is something that occupies me a lot,
对此事我思考良久
I'll be honest with you, because I sometimes think...
说实话 我有时候会想
"Oh, have I done enough now?"
我这辈子活够了吗
OTHERS: Yes. -No.
-够了 -别闹
No, you know, when?
你们知道 在哪个点
When would it be appropriate for me to think,
什么时候我会觉得合适开始思考
"Time to end."
是时候结束了
OTHERS: Now. -No.
-就是现在 -别这样
-May I get on with it? -Yeah, do. Do it now.
-我能继续吗 -继续 现在就做了断
No, what I want to say is, OK...
我的意思是
I'll get the forms, there can't be many.
我帮你拿申请表 不会有很多的
The time comes... Ssh!
时辰到了
The time, I think, comes when you stop wanting to be an idiot.
做了断的时机 我觉得是当你不想再犯傻了
That's the time when you've done enough.
我觉得这就代表着你的时辰已到
- I know what you mean. - No, actually, you are right,
-我懂你的意思 -你说得有道理
cos I think it's the moment where you go into a big department store,
我觉得 当你走进百货商店
and you go into the kitchenware section, and you see a tea cosy,
来到厨具专柜 看见茶壶套
but you don't put it on your head.
但却没有把它套在头上
-Exactly.
一针见血
Not putting things on your head is a sign it's time.
不再把东西套着头上就是丧钟啊
And the time you don't want to put gloves on your ears
不想把手套戴耳朵上
and pretend to be a reindeer.
假扮驯鹿时也是啊
-I think that's just you, Hammond. -It's just me, isn't it?
-我觉得就你一个人会这样 -就我一个
Here's the moment I think you know.
有这么一个时刻我觉得你们都懂
You're driving up a motorway. There's a train track next to you.
你在高速上开车 边上就是铁轨
A train comes. It could be one of those fast ones.
火车开来 可能还是高铁
The day when you don't try and race the train,
当你不再试着和火车比速度
that's the day.
那天就是了
-Yes. -I have to race the train.
-对 -我一定得和火车比赛
I have to go faster than the train
我一定要超过火车
so everyone on the train looks at me and goes,
这样火车上的乘客看到我
"I've made the wrong travel choice.
就会想火车是个错误的选择
"I should have gone in the car. It's quicker."
我应该开车 会更快
If you're ever on a train and you look out of the window,
你如果哪天在火车上 看向窗外
you're overtaking me and I can't be bothered to race you,
发现你超过了我 我也不想和你比赛
it's because I'm on my way to the new Dutch death clinic.
那我就是正在赶往荷兰死亡诊所
And that is the end of Conversation Street.
唠嗑街环节到此结束
Now, if you have children,
如果你有小孩
there's every chance they'll spend every spare second they have
他们会抓住所有机会把所有的空闲时间
playing Zombie Splatter 7 ,
拿来玩Zombie Splatter 7
or some other such computer game,
或其他电动
but what about more traditional board games?
至于传统的桌游
Kids these days say they're not interested in such games,
现在的小孩表示没兴趣
but I believe they would be if they were bigger
但我相信只要放大规模 而且有车
and involved cars.
他们就有兴趣了
To prove our point,
为了证明这一点
we've come here, to the countryside.
我们跑到了这个荒郊野外
And on the board-game front,
桌游的部分
we shall start with a classic.
我们选了一个经典款
A game where two players try and guess where each other's ships are,
两个玩家猜测对方的船在哪里
and then blow them up by firing missiles at them.
用飞弹击沉
It's a simple game,
简单易懂
and, as such, if you want to play it with cars,
而且如果你要用汽车来玩这个
you don't need much.
不需要太多准备
In fact, all you need
事实上 你只需要
is a massive former Cold War airfield
一个巨大的冷战时期的机场
with enough tarmac to accommodate the board for your board game.
用飞机跑道来当桌游的盘面
With a big enough slab of airfield,
有了足够大的飞机场后
you can then lay out your grid,
你可以开始画格子
onto which you can place your battleships.
用来摆你的战舰
And all you need for that
而你只需要
is several thousand pounds' worth of old cars.
一些值几千块英镑的旧车
But not any old cars.
但可不是随便什么旧车都行
This stretch limo, for example,
例如这个加长礼车
may have seen active service on hundreds of hen nights,
可能已经服役了数百场的单身派对
but it makes the perfect aircraft carrier.
但是可以完美胜任航空母舰
And then there's this Toyota Prius.
接着是这个丰田普瑞斯
Its electric engine makes it perfect as a submarine,
它的电动马达造就了一艘完美的潜水艇
silent running.
安静无声
And then there's this Chrysler PT Cruiser convertible.
然后是这台敞篷克莱斯勒PT漫步者
There is no naval equivalent for this car,
没有军舰跟它对应
but who cares if we blow it up?
但它炸了也没人在意
Because it is, after all, crap.
毕竟它就是个垃圾
And speaking of blowing up, we now come to the missiles.
说到炸掉 谈谈飞弹吧
For these, you need a car that is frightening and lethal.
你需要骇人且致命的车款
A car that strikes fear into other motorists.
让其他驾驶者心生恐惧
And what better car could there be for this job
为了达成这个任务 没有什么能比
than the magnificent G-Wiz?
伟大的 G-Wiz 更能胜任了
All I needed now was an opponent,
现在就只差对手了
a board-game veteran,
一个经验丰富的桌游玩家
a man who thinks Call Of Duty
一个认为 使命召唤 指的是
is a visit to the lavatory.
上厕所的男人
That's excellent, Hammond. You've thought of everything.
干得好 哈蒙德 真是周到
I know, I have. Containers as the fence.
没错 货柜来作栅栏
A fireman, in case things get out of hand.
消防员 为了避免状况失控
A health-and-safety bloke to stop us blowing ourselves up.
医护人员避免我们把自己炸飞
Cars that look exactly like ships. The lot.
超像船的车 等等
But how will you fire the missiles at the cars?
不过你要怎么发射飞弹
Well, that is the real genius in my plan.
这是我计划中的亮点
Easy, powerful and proven.
简单 威力强大且可靠
Fire the G-Wiz missiles with the movie cannon.
用特技专用加农炮把G-Wiz射出去
-You reckon that's accurate enough? -Well, it's a cannon.
-你觉得准度够吗 -这是个加农炮
But you've got to hit a specific square.
可是你必须命中指定的格子
You aim the cannon. You adjust the trajectory and the elevation.
你调整弹道和高度来瞄准
-You can work that out? -It's a cannon.
-你觉得能成么 -这是个加农炮
To shut James up, I took one of the spare cars
为了让詹姆斯闭嘴 我拿了一辆备用的车
to demonstrate a practice shot.
来做示范射击
Right, we're all set.
嗯 准备好了
It's fully charged. Pressure's good. Fire.
完全充气 压力到位 发射
JAMES: I had a better idea for the weapons-launching system.
我想到了一种更好的武器发射系统
So, there you go.
就是它
You call out the grid reference that you want,
你喊出盘面上的坐标
and the driver just manoeuvres the jib exactly over that square,
驾驶把吊臂移到那一格上方
and then drops the G-Wiz missile.
然后释放G-Wiz飞弹
It is absolutely unerringly accurate.
绝对精确 没有误差
I like that.
我喜欢
Unlike everything else I've done here, with all this stuff,
不像我在这里做过的任何事 有了这些
this is all things you can do at home in your garden.
你完全可以在自家花园弄这个
RICHARD: With the giant containers
利用巨大的货柜
making sure neither of us could see what the other was doing,
确保我们都看不到对方在做什么之后
...James and I moved our battleships into place.
我和詹姆斯安排好了自己的战舰
And with the board laid out, it was time to play.
盘面布置妥当 可以开打了
Right, the hen-night limos each require two hits to be sunk.
礼车需要两发飞弹才能击沉
Both the motorhomes, they each require two hits to be sunk as well.
房车也是需要两发才会沉
And then my Prius and your PT Cruiser,
然后我的普瑞斯和你的PT漫步者
they each require one to be sunk.
都是一发就沉
We've got ten G-Wiz missiles each.
每人有十颗G-Wiz飞弹
Five hits needed to win. Got it?
命中五次才赢 懂了吗
Yes, right.
好 懂了
Having won the toss, James would be first to fire,
掷硬币的结果 詹姆斯先攻
but I had a cunning plan to thwart him.
但我有个狡猾的计划来扰乱他
What I've done is put a couple of my ships right out on the edges,
我把一些船摆在边上
because James will think, "Hammond's a bit thick,
因为詹姆斯会想 哈蒙德有点蠢
and it's a typically amateurish tactic to put your ships on the edge,
把船摆在边上是标准的外行作风
so that's what he'll have done."
他一定会这么干
But then he'll think, "Hang on.
然后他会想 等等
Even Hammond's not that thick.
连哈蒙德都没那么蠢
He just wants me to think he's thick,
他想要让我觉得他很蠢
so he'll have put his cars in the middle."
所以他会把船摆在中间
James will then not go for the edges,
所以詹姆斯不会打边上
he'll go for the middle.
他会打中间
But my ships will be at the edges.
可是我的船在边上
It's like a... double, or even a triple bluff.
这是双重 甚至三重的误导
Now, Hammond is a bit thick, really,
哈蒙德真的有点蠢
so I reckon he'll have put his all around the edges.
所以我猜他会把船全部摆在边上
D2, please.
请瞄准D2
Fire!
开火
-What was that? -It was my limo.
打中了啥 打中我加长轿车了
Hit on your limo on D2, thank you. Your shot.
在D2击中了你的加长轿车 承让 该你了
Red crane driver, I'd like C4, please. C4.
红吊车司机 请瞄准C4谢谢 C4
Fire!
开火
That's a miss.
没打中
C4, miss.
C4 不中
Back to my original theory.
回到我刚才说的
Hammond will have gone along the edge,
哈蒙德肯定会靠着边摆
I'm pretty confident in that.
这点我很肯定
So is it there, or is it there?
所以到底是这边还是那边呢
Green crane driver, fire at D1.
绿吊车司机 瞄准D1
Fire!
开火
-Yes! -You sank my limousine!
-漂亮 -你击沉了我的加长轿车
One sinking to me, a miss for Admiral Hammond.
我击落了一艘 海军上将哈蒙德射失一发
And you've overdone the explosives.
你炸药搞得太多了
One plan would be, if you're playing this at home,
如果你打算在家玩这个的话 一个方法就是
do it on a day when there's a lot of barbecues in the area.
选个附近好多人搞烧烤的日子玩
That way, people will just think, "Well, yeah,
这样人们就会说 哦
it's a big barbecue they're having next door."
隔壁家烧烤搞得挺大啊
RICHARD: With my aircraft carrier gone
由于我损失了一艘航母
and James's fleet unscathed, I had to break my duck.
詹姆斯的舰队毫发无损 我得抓紧拿个一血了
I'd like you to hit B2, please.
给我冲着B2来一发 谢谢
Damn!
靠
B2. Well...
B2 不
Well, there's no... Where are they?!
不 这根本 他到底在哪啊
I've just got a feeling.
我有一种预感
B1. B1, please.
B1 B1 谢谢
Red crane driver, can I have square A1?
红吊车司机 我要打A1
Fire!
开火
Yes! Come on!
漂亮 怎么样
Oh, you are on the run! That is it! Want to give up?
快逃命吧 你完了 投降吗
You've sunk my Cruiser.
你击沉了我的巡洋舰
So that's a big red kill on A1. Boom!
所以是在A1格的一次暴击 砰
But James wasn't taking this lying down.
但是詹姆斯不会就这么束手就擒
C3. Fire!
C3 开火
Yes!
漂亮
You hit my submarine,
你击中了我的潜艇
my invisible, silent-running Prius.
我隐形静默的普锐斯
RICHARD: I am losing badly.
我现在大比分落后
I've scored only one hit, he's scored three.
我只击中了一次 而他有三次
But then the game started to turn,
但接着战局开始转折
as James had a run of three straight misses.
詹姆斯连续失手了三次
JAMES: Fire!
开火
It was a miss! Ha-ha!
你又射偏了 哈哈
Thank you. I'm closing down my options.
谢谢 我在缩小攻击范围
It would close your options down further if you were to hit rather than miss.
你要是打中 岂不能把范围缩更小么
Which was exactly what I was now doing.
比如说我就是
B3, please.
B3 谢谢
A3, please.
A3 谢谢
Yes!
漂亮
You've sunk my battleship.
你击沉了我的战列舰
I am raining down destruction
我的连环打击
on your dwindling fleet of doomed ships.
让你舰队日益萎缩 你早晚要完
You loser. Ha-ha!
你个输家 哈哈
No, I'm not losing. We're neck and neck.
我哪完了 咱俩现在平手好吧
Annoyingly, James was right.
讨厌的是 詹姆斯说的对
I still had my battleship Winnebago,
我还剩下温内贝戈号战列舰
温内贝戈 房车品牌
and he still had his stretched aircraft carrier,
他则还有加长航母
both of which needed two hits to destroy.
这俩都需要双发才能摧毁
It was May's turn to play.
轮到梅出手了
B2.
B2
RICHARD: Critical stage of the game now.
比赛到了最关键的时候了
A hit now and I'm in trouble.
如果他命中我就麻烦大了
Fire!
开火
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
漂亮 漂亮 漂亮
It shouldn't feel so good, but it does.
我不该这么兴奋 但我控制不住啊
Oh.
嗷
It's gonna be here.
就在这一块区域
Red crane, target C1, please. C1.
红队吊车 瞄准C1谢谢 C1
Fire!
开火
Hard luck, Horatio Hammond.
真是不幸 霍雷肖哈蒙德
恶搞 霍雷肖 纳尔逊 英国皇家海军之魂
All I've got to do now,
我现在需要做的
get inside Richard Hammond's mind.
就是要钻到理查德哈蒙德脑子里
An awful place, admittedly, but if I can just get in there for a second,
不是什么好地方 我承认 但只需进去一会
which way has he put it?
弄明白他的船是朝哪个方向
There and there; there and there; there and there?
是朝下 是朝上 还是朝右
C2.
C2
Fire!
开火
That'll be a miss.
这发打偏了
That, Captain May, was a miss!
刚才那发 梅舰长 打偏了
However, while James now had to choose between just two squares,
但是 詹姆斯只需从两个格子里选一个
I was looking at a choice of six.
而我则要面临六选一
Red crane, target C2, please. C2.
红队吊车 瞄准C2谢谢 C2
Red crane, fire!
红队吊车 开火
I meant C3! I meant...
我是说C3 我是说
Yes!
好样的
Oh, yes! Yes!
漂亮
Bollocks.
混蛋
RICHARD: That mistaken shot wasn't just a hit,
这错误的一发不止击中了
it had changed everything.
它改变了整个局面
Because I said C2, when actually I meant three,
因为我说C2 实际想说的是3
in case it was there,
是在这里
that's a kill - bang -
这里击中了 砰
which means it has to be there.
所以下一发肯定是这了
It can't be here or here, so I've got him.
没别的可能了 我赢定他了
James, you do know what that means, don't you?
詹姆斯 你知道这意味着什么吧
Yes, I've just worked it out.
没错 我刚弄明白
I've got to get this right, otherwise you've won.
我这发必须猜对 不然你就赢了
-Do you want to surrender? -No, I don't!
-你要投降吗 -才不
JAMES: So, I was now faced with the choice
所以我现在面临着
that would decide the game.
改变游戏的抉择
A2 or B3?
A2 还是 B3
A2, B3. What would Richard Hammond do?
A2 B3 哈蒙德会怎么做
Green-crane driver...
绿吊车司机
Oh, God.
哦 天啊
Come on, you bewildered old spaniel - miss.
来啊 你这晕头转向的老猎犬 不中啊
Right. Fire!
好了 发射
Oh, God!
天啊
Hammond!
哈蒙德
RICHARD: Best of three?
三局两胜么
JEREMY: I bet...
我打赌
I bet the makers of Sony PlayStation are quaking in their boots.
我打赌造索尼PS的人腿都软了
Well, I wouldn't be surprised.
没错 我一点也不惊讶
-They will go, "Oh, my..." -I know. There's the future.
-他们会 哦天啊 -我知道 这就是未来
-That was a total waste of time. -Well, now, hang on.
-简直浪费时间 -等等
No, we destroyed a PT Cruiser, a Prius and many G-Wizs.
我们炸了辆PT漫步者 一辆普锐斯  好多 G-Wiz
Well, that's true, yes. But James...
也没错啦 但詹姆斯
James?
詹姆斯
Never mind. Let's move on to Celebrity Brain Crash.
随便吧 让我们进入明星脑碰脑环节
This week...
本周
This week, we don't just have one star,
我们不止请了一位嘉宾
we have several.
来了好多个
They're one of the biggest bands
他们是来自荷兰的
ever to come out of Holland,
最成功的乐队之一
and they're going to begin here,
他们将在这里
in the sixth largest port in the world...
世界上第六大港口
by performing their biggest hit,
演奏最脍炙人口的歌曲
by which I mean... their hit.
我是说 他们的金曲
Ladies and gentlemen, Golden Earring!
女士们先生们 金耳环乐队
RICHARD: And there they are.
他们就在那了
I tell you what,
要我说
we ought to make the lights go a bit better.
我们应该把灯光调更好点
Can we dim the lights? That's better. A bit more rock 'n' roll.
我们能把灯调暗些吗 好多了 更摇滚了
What is their hit?
他们的金曲是啥
Well, this is Holland, birthplace of the speed camera.
好吧 这是荷兰 测速摄像头的诞生地
It's obvious. Radar Love.
很明显 要唱 雷达的爱 啊
d I've been drivin' all night My hands wet on the wheel d
我彻夜开车 汗水浸湿方向盘
RICHARD: Oh...
哦
JEREMY: OK, ladies and gentlemen, erm...
啊 女士们先生们
...there's a cable's gone into the sea here, and...
电线落到了海里 然后
...Golden Earring have been electrocuted.
金耳环被电死了
Does that mean they're not coming on, then?
就是说他们来不了咯
Well, James, they've been subjected to a lethal dose of electricity
詹姆斯 他们被致命电流击中
and are now lying on the ground, sizzling, so it's no.
现在躺在地上 滋滋冒烟 所以来不了
-They're not, no. -OK, OK.
-来不了了 -好吧 好吧
That is a very grisly scene. I apologise for that, everybody.
这一幕很可怕 我向大家道歉
Erm... Probably not as grisly, though,
呃 可能也没外人从窗口
as if you're looking at us from out there.
看我们来得可怕
-Eh? -Well, think about it.
-怎么 -来 你想想
-Oh, yeah! -Yeah.
-哦 对哦 -是啊
We are standing in a window in a Dutch port,
我们站在荷兰海港边的窗口
bathed in red light...
开着红灯
荷兰红灯区
...and we've got no trade lining up.
而且我们现在也没活可干
-Nobody's here. -No.
-都没人了 -不
No, I know! I know! I've had an idea.
我知道了 我有个主意
I've had an idea of how we can fill the time
我有个填补已故的金耳环乐队
that would have been taken up by the late Golden Earring.
留下来的时间空白的好主意
You see, the thing is...
你瞧
Can we make the lights go white again now? Pretend that never happened.
我们能让灯变白吗 假装什么都没发生过
Good. See, the thing is that, in Holland,
好 你瞧 在荷兰
there are these motorist accessory stores, OK?
有好多汽车用品商店
-Oh, yeah. -They're open all night. The place is full.
-哦对 -通宵营业啊 人满为患
We went to one last night and bought a load of amazing stuff
昨晚我们也去了 买了好多好东西
you can use on the road.
你能开车时用到的
Bring it over here. Let's show you a couple of things,
我们拿出来 给你们看几个
I mean, this, for example.
比方说 这玩意
It's an incredible safety device.
这个安全装备简直逆天了
This is very clever, because in a lot of car crashes,
聪明极了 因为在很多车祸里
people bite their tongues, sometimes off.
人们会咬到舌头 甚至会咬下来
But by wearing this neat safety device,
但戴了这个安全设备以后
no way is he biting his tongue.
他就不可能咬到舌头了
Look at that! Perfectly safe. That is clever.
看呐 完全安全 太聪明了
Unbelievable. And then you can get traffic cones
难以相信 然后还有能放杂物箱里的
that fit in the glovebox.
锥形交通路障
-This is one here.
这个就是
RICHARD: Yeah. -It's not funny stuff, this is safety material.
不开玩笑 这可是安全装备
-Another one. -These are compact, so you can fit them in your boot.
-另一个 -它们很便携 能装到后备箱里去
The thing is, though, OK, in America,
问题是 在美国
as I'm sure you know, there are high-occupancy vehicle lanes.
你应该知道 有载人专用车道
Er... You're not allowed to go in them
除非你车里有2人或以上同乘
unless you've got two or more people in the car.
不然你不能进这车道
We've always been very worried in Europe
我们很担心什么时候欧洲
that this idea is gonna come over here,
这个政策也会实施
but the Dutch have it covered,
但荷兰人替我们想好了
because in these motorist accessory shops,
因为在汽配店里
you can buy inflatable people.
你能买到充气的人啊
-We've got one here.
这就有一个
-Very clever, this. Very clever. -Isn't it?
-太聪明了这 -怎么不是
The only slight issue is they do take a lot of effort to blow up.
唯一的小毛病是 它们吹起来特费劲
It's hard work doing.
是个体力活
It doesn't matter, though, because here's the thing.
没关系 这就有办法
OK, if you arrive at one of those
你开到那
high-occupancy vehicle lanes,
载人专用车道里
then you pull over on the hard shoulder -
然后你在应急车道停车
just pass the Dutchie on the left-hand side here -
超过左手边这些荷兰人
and then use your engine to blow up
然后用你的发动机
your inflatable person.
来吹这些充气人
So I'm going to do that now, just to show you how unbelievably easy this is.
我现在就演示给你们看 这有多容易
Are we ready?
准备好了么
I'll just er... put a bit of fuel in there.
我先 加点汽油
And here we go.
好了
Why have you put your fingers in your ears? It's only a V8.
你干嘛要用手塞住耳朵 区区V8而已
It's virtually silent.
几乎没声音的
Here we go.
你看
Behold.
等等
What the...?
我去
Right, the erm...
好了
The inflatable person has split. There's--
充气人炸了
Oh, dear.
哦糟糕
Mine's all right.
我的没问题啊
Let's move on, shall we? Tonight we are in Morocco,
我们继续把 今晚我们在摩洛哥
for what was supposed to be a sensible sports-car test of my Mazda MX-5
本应是一次理性的跑车评测 我的马自达MX-5
versus Bob Marley's Norfolk-built Zenos.
对阵鲍勃马利的诺福克产Zenos
鲍勃 马利 雷鬼之父 又是飞叶子梗
Unfortunately, the ape turned up, uninvited,
不幸的是 猩猩他不请自来
in a ridiculously expensive Alfa Romeo.
还带了一辆贵的离谱的阿尔法罗密欧
Yes, I did.
没错
And when we left the action,
之前的节目里
I decided to see which of the cars was the lightest
我想要知道这几辆车哪辆最轻
by building some rudimentary scales -
就打算做一个简易的秤
a job that these two thought would be... beyond me.
这俩人却觉得我搞不定
JEREMY: Despite the cynicism of my colleagues,
尽管被我那俩同事看不起
the next morning, my scales were ready.
但是第二天早上 我的秤就做好了
-Wow. -Yeah.
-行 -厉害
JAMES: Even more startling was Jeremy's choice of counterweight.
更让人吃惊的是杰里米选择的砝码
How are you gonna get it on there?
你打算怎么把它弄上去
-It's gonna jump. -Oh, yeah, they're big jumpers, cows.
-它会跳 -哦对 牛是跳跃能手
-Look, it wants to. -He's limbering up,
-你看 它主动想跳 -它正在热身
he's getting ready, you can tell.
你能感觉它准备好了
-Up you come. -It's not gonna jump. They can't jump.
-走你 -它不会跳的 人家跳不起来
Up you come.
走你
On the off chance that this isn't a jumping cow,
假设如果这不是那种能跳的牛
which it might not be, I think you need a ramp.
我只是假设 我觉得你得弄个斜坡
You hold that. I shall go and make a ramp.
那你牵着 我去做个斜坡来
-Hello. Hello. -Hello, nice cow.
-你好 -你好啊 好牛牛
Oh, it's bonded with you, Jeremy. It's bonded.
哦 杰里米它喜欢上你了
JEREMY: Soon, without any help at all,
很快 没有外人的帮助下
I had fashioned a makeshift ramp.
我就造了个临时坡道
RICHARD: Very good. Well done.
真棒 干得好
That was quick and effective.
真是又快又好
JEREMY: Unfortunately, the cow had wandered off,
不幸的是 那头牛不知跑哪去了
so I had to draft in a substitute.
所以我只能找来个替代品
-Go on, camel.
上来 骆驼
-Come on, camel. -Come on.
-上来 骆驼 -上去
Come on, camel. Come on.
上来啊 骆驼 上来
Come on. Come on.
来 来
He's not gonna go on.
它上不去
Up you come. Come on.
走你 上来
Come on. Can you push him? Oh, no.
上来 你能推它一把吗 不
Not really, cos they kick your balls off if you do that. Let me...
不行 它会把你的蛋蛋踢掉的 我来
David Attenborough has never said that.
大卫爱登堡绝对不会说这话
大卫爱登堡 英国著名播音员 自然保护学者
JEREMY: Eventually, I had some success.
最终 我还是有所收获的
This is good. We are getting there.
不错 我们快了
We are building up a big Christmas dinner.
这就快够做一桌圣诞大餐的了
JEREMY: And then the original cow came back.
然后原先的那只牛又回来了
-Come on. RICHARD: Dr Thinklittle.
-上来 -你就不能动动脑子
JEREMY: Come on. Come on. RICHARD: My camel's going over here.
来 来 我的骆驼要往那走
Good cow.
好牛牛
-Tragically, however... -...it's not enough.
但是悲剧的是 还是不够沉啊
Could you go and get another cow?
你能再去找一头牛来吗
Come on, small cow.
过来 小牛牛
JEREMY: He's on. Right, excellent.
它上来了 太好了
-Good, good, good. -Jeremy?
-好好好 -杰里米
-Yes? -This is far...
啥 这也太
-Oh, my God! -I don't want to be here for this!
-我的天 -我想下去
I'm on some scales. Its carrot's come out.
我在一个秤上 然后牛的胡萝卜就出来了
-Are they both boy cows? -Yeah, they're both boys.
-它俩都是公的吗 -对他俩都是公的
Yeah. Oh, no. This is quite bad.
是 哦不 坏了
-I'm... Yeah. -I really am alarmed.
我 嗯 我是真的在害怕
I'm stuck on a porn set.
我困在A片片场了
Am I part of this? Is this a threesome?
我也算在里面吗 这算3P吗
He's trod on a turk... No, he hasn't.
它踩到火鸡了 不它没有
JEREMY: More importantly, the whole cast of our porn film
更重要的是 我们整个A片的剧组加在一起
still weighed less than the Mazda.
也还是比马自达轻
Chickens. Hello, chickies.
鸡 你们好啊 鸡鸡们
-It's not enough, is it? -No.
还不够是吧 是
It doesn't make... Jeremy, this is complete nonsense.
这根本就 杰里米 这办法根本不行
RICHARD: Cow sex! No!
牛做爱啦 不
Come on, we go. On you go.
来 上来 走你
RICHARD: I'm not convinced that this isn't...
我实在没法相信这
Oh, the goat's escaped.
噢 山羊跑了
RICHARD: At this stage, we explained to Jeremy
事到如今 我们跟杰里米解释了
that animals cannot be used as counterweights.
动物不能用来当砝码
Right, no, you may have a point.
好吧 你们说的也许有道理
I think it's better if I kill them.
干脆杀了它们吧
-What? -Well, if they're dead, they won't mind.
啥 如果它们都死了 就无所谓了
JEREMY: This plan made the job much easier.
这个方法让一切都变得容易了
JEREMY: Oh, hello!
你们看
My experiment has worked.
我的实验成功了
Wow! We have a figure.
喔 我们得到数据了
JAMES: For the record, it weighs two cows,
我宣布 马自达的重量是 两头牛
two legs of cows - brackets, rear -
两条牛腿 括弧 后腿
one camel and three goats.
一头骆驼和三只山羊
That's incredible!
太好了
The most exciting thing I've ever been involved in.
这是我干过最刺激的事了
JEREMY: Having established the weight of the Mazda,
在测完马自达的重量后
it was time to do the Zenos.
要来测测Zenos了
JEREMY: Hammond, reverse off down my superb ramp.
哈蒙德 从我做的完美坡道上倒下去
-Whoa! It's... -I'm gonna walk this way.
-喔 -这 我最好是往这边走
Why is it doing that? James counterbalances with you.
为啥会这样 詹姆斯用你的体重去平衡一下
JEREMY: Hang on. That's not gone well.
等下 还是不行
JAMES: Yeah, it has. -No, it's moved!
行了啊 不 整个在移动
RICHARD: Oh, this is... Now the back wheels have come off!
啊 这简直 这下后轮都掉下来了
Somebody get on! The whole crew!
找谁赶紧上去 全体剧组成员
-What's happened?
发生了什么
JAMES: Oh, God!
哦 天呐
JEREMY: No, there's no point doing that, Hammond.
哈蒙德 这样一点用都没有
We need to think this through.
我们这回可得想清楚喽
Hang on. I've got an idea.
等等 我有主意了
If you get off there, this side will go up.
如果你们从那下去 这里会抬高
Then you put the ramp under the back wheels of the Mazda
然后当它再下来时候
when it comes down again.
把斜坡放到马自达后轮下
-So you all need to get off. -Right, I'm off.
-所以你们都要下去 -好 我下去了
Hang on. Are you going up now?
等等 你升上去了么
-I think so. -No, we need...
-应该是 -不我们需要
I know, everybody has to go there.
我知道了 所有人都要到对面去
-On that side. Yeah. -Everybody, all the crew.
-另一边 对 -所有人 所有工作人员
All the chunkier lads, if you get on that one.
所有壮小伙 如果上了那边
JEREMY: How did we get into this position?
我们怎么沦落到现在这种地步
Somebody pull on the front, just to tip it.
来人拉一下前面 让后面翘起来
JEREMY: And then we will move this ramp.
然后我们就能动斜坡了
Hello? Can we have all of...
哈罗 我们能让所有的
-He's down now! RICHARD: Am I gonna die?
-垮了垮了 我要死了吗
Am I dead? Am I dead?
我死了么 死了么
JEREMY: Thanks to our fluent French,
多亏我们流利的法语
we were able to get the forklift driver to help us.
我们能请到叉车司机来帮忙
The Mazda...
马自达
Erm...
呃
JAMES: Reverse a vous la ramp,
你倒个坡
avec introduce la ramp... Yeah.
你坡个推
JEREMY: Then the authorities arrived.
然后来了个官员
-Ah, les animaux? -Yes, les animaux.
-啊 动物 -是的 动物
Wait. Erm...
等等 呃
Is it a Probleme?
有什么问题吗
James, it's not acceptable in Morocco
詹姆斯 在摩洛哥
to kill animals to establish the weight of a car, so...
杀动物来称车重是不被允许的 所以
It's not acceptable in Morocco?
这事情在哪都不允许吧
JEREMY: Having established nothing at all,
白忙活一阵后
we were all ordered to leave,
我们被要求离开
which made Hammond very cheesed off with me.
这让哈蒙德对我非常生气
RICHARD: You're a bloody idiot!
你这大蠢蛋
JEREMY: Funny!
可笑
I think he's angry, isn't he?
我猜他生气了 是吧
And I wasn't in James's good books, either.
我在詹姆斯那也印象不好
Clarkson!
克拉克森
What's the matter?
怎么了
I want the steering wheel back, you muppet!
快还我方向盘 你个蠢蛋
-I haven't got it. -You have!
-我才没拿 -肯定拿了
I haven't. One of those goats has got it.
才没有 肯定是羊叼走
Goats can't pick things up.
羊没法叼东西的
RICHARD: With his wheel retrieved, we set off.
找回他的方向盘之后 我们上路了
And soon, James and I decided
很快 詹姆斯和我决定
something needed to be done.
有件事必须要做
Jeremy, are you there?
杰里米 你在吗
Yes, I am.
我在听
Oh, good. Erm...
那就好 呃
Look, just...
那个 我说
Er... Just bear with me, OK?
呃 请原谅我这么说
This isn't really working as well as we'd hoped at the moment,
事情的进展 和我们预期的不太一样
so we think it would be better if we went our own way
所以我俩觉得目前更好的选择是
and you went yours.
我们各走各的
Are you in on this, James?
你也这么想吗 詹姆斯
Well, the thing is that we had conceived quite an interesting test
是这样 我们想出了这个
between an everyday sports car and a hardcore sports car.
日常跑车对比硬派跑车的有趣测试
And, I mean, it's not you.
我的意思是 并不是针对你
But, I mean, really, it's the Alfa. The Alfa doesn't fit.
而是阿尔法 它并不适合这个测试
Right, well, OK. Erm...
好吧 我明白了
I'll leave you two alone.
那我就甩下你俩了
And I do mean alone,
是真的要甩下
because... I'm going to take the film crews with me.
因为 我会把摄制组都带走
Now that we're alone,
现在只剩下我们了
I could prattle on for hours
我可以向你们唠叨几个小时
about what the Alfa Romeo badge means,
阿尔法罗密欧的徽标有什么含义
and how, with its carbon-fibre tub,
而因为这个碳纤维单体壳
this isn't really a sports car.
他并不完全是一辆跑车
It's more a... scaled-down, cut-price LaFerrari.
更像是尺寸和价格上都按比例缩小的拉法
But I've had a better idea.
但我有个更好的主意
What I did was find a wonderful piece of road...
我要做的就是找一段风景优美的路
...and then shut up,
然后把嘴闭上
so the pictures could do the talking.
让画面来诠释阿尔法的美
旋转 像涡流里的盘旋
像前进的车轮卷卷
像你寻觅已久的圆
在你脑海的风车回旋
如你沿隧道而行
择其深处而进
琢出空谷铭心
日光再也不明
如不停旋转之门
如日渐遗忘之梦
如那涟漪浅浅
谁人投石在溪间
宛若时钟之手轻拂
时光流逝在面肤
世界就如苹果
在宙间旋转静默
像你寻觅已久的圆
在你脑海的风车回旋
That's the thing about this Alfa -
这就是阿尔法
if you talk about it, you're gonna criticise it.
一旦评价起它 就会去批判它
If you just look at it... you're gonna fall in love. Oh, hello.
只需看着它 就会爱上它 噢 瞧啊
Mate! Mate! Thank God you're here!
伙计 快来看 幸好你来了
JEREMY: What's the matter with him?
他这是抽什么风
Well, for the first time in my life,
我有生以来第一次
I'm rather glad you're here, because...
乐意看见你 那是因为
he thinks he's discovered an ancient civilisation.
他觉得自己发现了古代文明
And he got very excited,
所以变得异常兴奋
and I couldn't say, "No, Hammond, it's not real."
我又不忍心戳穿 这都是假的
It's a film set.
这是电影布景
That is where they filmed Asterix And Obelix ,
那里是用来拍 高卢英雄 的
and that is where they film Game Of Thrones .
那里是用来拍 权力的游戏 的
Yeah, I know that, but he thinks it's real.
我知道 但他以为是真的
He thinks aliens have come down
他觉得是外星人来了
and that everything that universities in Britain know about Ancient Egypt,
而英国高校的学者们对古埃及 古希腊
Ancient Greece, Ancient Rome, is all wrong.
以及古罗马的认识都是错的
Which feet last trod these steps?
上一次踏上这些台阶的是谁
Were they even human?
他们是人类吗
Maybe they were that big.
没准他们就是这么大
This was actually used in The Jewel Of The Nile .
这是在 尼罗河之宝 中使用过的道具
-Was it? -Yeah.
-真的吗 -是的
Starring Kathleen Turner, Michael Douglas,
主演有凯瑟琳 特纳  迈克尔 道格拉斯
and, I think, Danny DeVito.
我记得还有丹尼 德维托
Hammond probably thinks that it's a spaceship.
哈蒙德没准会认为这是宇宙飞船
-That's how they got here. -(CHUCKLES)
外星人就是这么来的
It's like touching hands...
就好像是在和
...across the millennia.
一千年前握手
These were not primitive people.
他们可不是原始人
JEREMY: While Indiana Hammond
当印第安纳哈蒙德
印第安纳琼斯梗
continued his deluded ramblings,
继续无头苍蝇般漫游时
I came up with an idea.
我想出了个好主意
I tell you what this place has never been used as.
我告你 这里从没被用来做过什么
-What? -A racetrack.
-什么 -赛道
JEREMY: Having convinced Richard
在说服理查德
we wouldn't anger the sleeping gods,
这样不会触怒沉睡的诸神之后
we made a circuit from the roads running through the studio lot.
我们在布景中建出了一条赛道
And then I went off to get changed.
然后我去换了身衣服
Wow! Hammond, Roger Moore isn't here.
哇 看呐 哈蒙德 没说罗杰 摩尔会来啊
罗杰 摩尔 第三任邦德扮演者
No, he's not, is he? What is that?
他没来对吧 这是啥
It's my Alfa Romeo racing suit.
这是我的阿尔法罗密欧赛车服
-Is it? -Yes, it is. Look at that.
-真的吗 -没错 你看
RICHARD: Oh! JEREMY: Peacock lining.
-噢  -孔雀毛内衬
RICHARD: That makes it better.
这样显得好多了
It's the Dick from Del Monte.
Del Monte的迪克
恶搞美国罐头食品大厂 Del Monte 的经典广告语
-The Cock from Del Monte.
Del Monted的Cock
the Man from Del Monte, he says Yes
The Dick from Del Monte, he says, "Ra-ra-ra!"
Del Monte的迪克 他说 啦啦啦
Del Monte的先生说 好
-In an Alfa Romeo-- JAMES: This is tremendous!
-这是辆阿尔法罗密欧 -太有意思了
这里改成了dick 双关 丁丁
船长又在复述中把dick通假成了cock
In an Alfa Romeo...
开着阿尔法罗密欧
...looking good is more important than looking where you're going.
看着帅比看着路更重要
-That's a shame. -When are you gonna do that?
-真可惜 -可你不看路怎么开
JEREMY: It was now time to get down to business.
开始来真的了
But first, we went out for some sighting laps.
首先跑几圈来熟悉赛道
It's all skiddy!
滑滑的
-Oh, this is very narrow. James did this.
这个门特别窄 詹姆斯故意搞的
That's only an inch wider than my car, you stupid man!
只比我的车宽了一寸 你个笨蛋
But I'm in!
但我进去了
I'm into ancient Egypt!
开进了古埃及时代
Oh, wow! Look at that! Paintings and everything!
哦 看看这些壁画和雕塑
JAMES: I'm gonna go around the unconvincing fighter jet.
我要绕过这个战斗机模型
JEREMY: Understeering like mad, that's not good. I must remember that.
推头很严重 不太妙 我得小心
The problem you have in the 4C is it's mid-engined,
4C 的发动机是中置的
which means, on a surface like this,
意味着在这种路面上
there's no weight over the front,
前轴没有足够的重量
and that means... no grip.
所以抓地力不足
RICHARD: Unlike the other two, this is front-engined,
不像另两个人 我的车是前置引擎的
so there's less weight on the back end,
后轴较轻
which would make for a livelier back end
使得车尾非常灵活
and more time enjoying oversteer.
享受漂移的乐趣
Oh, I'm gonna spin!
玩大了
That's bad! That's too much oversteer.
这样不行 飘过头了
JEREMY: Game Of Thrones set.
进入 权利的游戏 的片场
I mustn't think about Khaleesi.
不准意淫卡丽熙
Oh, no! Thinking about Khaleesi, it's bad!
啊 把持不住啊 糟糕
Don't think about Khaleesi!
不能想歪了
No!
废了
Holy crap!
天啊
It's a castle!
有座城堡
God, no! Nearly hit a bit of Nazareth then.
差点撞到拿撒勒古迹
耶稣出生地
Jesus would have been displeased.
上帝会生气的
JEREMY: Having got to know
熟悉了
our weird and demanding track,
我们奇怪而艰巨的赛道后
we began the timed laps, with James going first
我们开始做计时圈了 詹姆斯第一个出发
in his lightweight, powerful Norfolk-mobile.
开着他轻量化 大马力的诺福克小车
Right, are we ready, James May?
詹姆斯准备好了吗
In three, two, one... Begin!
三 二 一 出发
Oh, where's the bend? I don't...
咦 第一个弯在哪里
Oh, balls!
搞鬼啊
You know, what worries me most of all,
说实话我现在最担心的是
is the poor little man who's mortgaged his house to start Zenos.
那个倾家荡产开创 Zenos 品牌的人
And that he's lent it to us on the television.
他把车借给我们节目组
"And which one's driving it? Which...?"
请问是哪个主持开我们的车呢
"Oh, no."
废了
Right, now what do I do?
接下来怎么走
After my first-corner cock-up,
在我第一个弯失误以后
I was on the back foot, trying to make up time.
我处在劣势 要迎头赶上
Heading for Nazareth, I think.
下面应该是拿撒勒古迹
Whoa!
天啊
All over the place!
到处飘
Round and round the thingy.
绕过这个东西
Whoa!
喔
Fast, faster. Faster.
快 快 快
Well... this only goes up to 999 hours, sadly.
可惜这个秒表的量程只有 999 小时
JAMES: Right.
好吧
But it's OK, you were just in that time.
但不要紧 你刚好赶上了
Yeah, mm.
这么巧
James, did you manage to drive
詹姆斯 跑圈的时候
whilst dragging your face along the ground?
你的脸是一直在地上拖吗
A lot of dust comes in.
进了很多灰
-Why don't you wind the windows up?
为何不把窗户摇上了
You're funny men.
两个逗逼
RICHARD: Next, it was the turn of John Travolta.
接着就是约翰 屈伏塔出场了
约翰 屈伏塔 好莱坞影星
Never has anybody looked quite so good...
从没有人在刷圈时候
...on a timed lap.
穿这么帅过
In three, two, one... Go!
三 二 一 走
Right, let's make this count.
好 别浪费这机会
Narrow!
好窄
Sideways in linen!
亚麻西装漂移
Game Of Thrones set.
权利游戏布景到了
Understeering...
转向不足
Turn! Turn!
转啊 转啊
Come on, let's get that turbocharger singing!
来 让这涡轮唱起来
Kill it now!
这里踩到底
Well, he arrived.
总之 他到了
JAMES: Finally, Sir John Blashford-Hammond.
最后 约翰 布拉史福特哈蒙德 爵士
恶搞 约翰 布拉史福特 斯乃尔 英国探险家
-Ready? -Yes.
-预备 -好
In three, two, one... Go!
三 二 一 走
Right, this is it.
好了 来吧
I can't afford a single error.
容不得半点失误
Uh-oh! This is a hot lap!
哦 这圈很快
Here he comes.
他来了
No!
不要啊
And with that, back to the tent.
好吧 我们回到演播帐篷
Smashed it. Smashed it.
撞坏了 撞坏了
-Hang on a minute. -What?
-等等 -怎么
You know that Windmills Of Your Mind sequence in the car?
你 脑海的风车 那一段
-Yeah. -You made the Alfa look really good in that.
-恩 -你让阿尔法看起来真是漂亮
-Yes. -What if somebody buys one?
-没错 -如果有人真买这车
You don't want that on your conscience.
你良心会会不安吗
What do you mean? It was a brilliant... What?
你什么意思 这是个完美的
Anyway, anyway, I have the results here of the laps.
好了 好了 我这里有圈速啦
And er... well, in third place,
所以 第三名
you in the Zenos; second place, you in the Alfa;
你和Zenos 第二名 你和阿尔法
first place, the winner was me in the Mazda.
第一名 我和马自达
But it was a hollow victory,
但这是个无意义的胜利
because I ruined an ancient piece of sculpture.
因为我毁掉了一块古代雕塑
Yes, but here's the thing, OK?
事实是这样的
After the weight test and the speed test we did,
在我们做了重量测试和速度测试后
we've learned...
我们得到了
-...nothing. -Yeah, it's nothing. Nothing at all.
-毫无结果 -对 毫无结果 一点没有
Literally nothing at all.
真的完全没有
And on that terrible disappointment,
伴随着这令人十分沮丧的消息
I'm afraid it's time to end.
这期节目就到此为止了
Thank you so much for watching.
感谢收看
-See you next week. Goodbye. -Goodbye!
-下周再见 -再见